In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of Doshi Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, Doshi Marvelous Designer is used in this tutorial.
Although the version is not arranged around the virtual model, it can still be sealed.
But arranging the version in the right place will help you to complete the sealing of the version more conveniently.
Please open the project file you saved in the previous tutorial.
You can open the saved project by pressing Ctrl O.
I have saved two versions of the file, you can use any of them.
I use the T-Series version created in the 2D window.
First, select the move tool in the 3D window.
Select all the versions in the 3D window.
Then right-click on the selected version and select Rearrange 2D Arrangement Position.
The version will be rearranged in the 3D window according to the arrangement position in the 2D window.
We move them to other places, do not cover the virtual model, so as to arrange the version later.
Move the mouse to the virtual model display list.
Find the display virtual model arrangement point in the drop-down menu and select it.
These blue points around the virtual model are the arrangement points.
Observe these blue points carefully.
There are two types of blue points.
Some have a gray outer circle and some are not completely colored.
The gray outer circle is called the symmetrical arrangement point.
When a version with a symmetrical relationship is arranged on a symmetrical arrangement point,
its symmetrical version will also be automatically arranged on its symmetrical arrangement point.
Next, we will arrange the version around the virtual model through the arrangement point.
Use the move tool to select the front version.
Move the mouse and stop at the blue point.
You can see the effect of arranging the version in each arrangement point.
According to the preview effect, click on the appropriate point to arrange the version.
Since the front version has a symmetrical relationship,
when we arrange it on the symmetrical arrangement point,
the other front version will also be automatically arranged in the symmetrical position.
The back version is also arranged in the same way.
Since the versions are all arranged on the symmetrical arrangement point,
when we are dealing with the back version,
please rotate the view to the back of the model,
and then arrange it through the arrangement point to make it more intuitive.
Please note that the version in the 2D window is flat,
so in fact these two versions are on one side,
and we will merge these two side lines together.
Finally, let's arrange the sleeve.
Place the sleeve on the arrangement point on the side of the arm,
so that the middle line of the sleeve is on the side of the arm.
You can use the positioning ball or the attribute editor to adjust the arrangement position.
Drag and adjust the axis, or enter the specific number to adjust the position of the x-axis,
the position of the y-axis, and the diameter and direction to adjust the arrangement position.
In addition to the pocket version, the other versions are all arranged.
Now you can turn off the arrangement point.
Let's use the positioning ball to arrange the pocket version.
Drag the axis of the positioning ball to drag the version to the area near the pocket position outside the T-zone,
and then move it to the position of the pocket.
When the position of the positioning ball is moved,
you can select the positioning ball, the world coordinate,
and switch it to the world coordinate via the 3D background right-click.
Please save your file as a project file.
We will use it in the following tutorial.